Guide to the John Tabor Kempe Papers 1678-1782 (bulk 1752-1774) MS 344
New-York Historical Society
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1730-1775 (bulk 1753-1774), and Undated, 1730-1775 and Undated
  - Subseries 1: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, 1759-1775 and Undated
    Arranged alphabetically by sender. This subseries contains letters to John Tabor Kempe regarding various court cases, especially land conflicts, and requests for assistance. Prisoners writing from jail often plead their cases to Kempe, and describe conditions in jail. A number of items deal with the disputed area of the New Hampshire land claims, and rioting there. Frequent correspondents include Rutger Bleecker, Henry Chase, Ann Cock, William Cockburn, John Duncan, Richard Dysart, Abraham Hausbrouck, Sarah Hayward, Whitehead Hicks, Harmanus Schuyler, Peter Silvester, George Spencer, Thomas Swords, John Wetherhead, and Abraham Yates. In addition, there are several letters from John Tabor Kempe's brother, William Kempe, asking for assistance, clothes, and money.
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, A-Blanchard, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Bleecker-Browne, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Ca-Cl, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Co, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Cr-Cy, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, D, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, E-G, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, H, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, I-K, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Kempe family, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, L, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Ma-Mc, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Mi-Mu, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, N-R, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Sa-Si, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Sk-Sw, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, T, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, V, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, W-Y, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Received, Unidentified, 1759-1775 and Undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent (Copies/Drafts), 1759-1775
    Arranged alphabetically by recipient. This subseries contains letters regarding court cases, land issues (especially in Albany County), and financial matters. Frequent correspondents include Rutger Bleecker, John Bradstreet, William Cockburn, Sir William Johnson, Harmanus Schuyler, and Thomas Swords. Letters to Sir William Johnson deal with the Crown's land disputes with Native Americans, and contain Kempe's opinions on the use of Native Americans as trial witnesses, the legitimacy of lan patents purchased from "the Natives," and the Daniel Nimham case.
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, A-B, 1760-1775 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, C, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, D-F, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, G-J, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, K-Q, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, R-S, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, T-Y, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: John Tabor Kempe, Letters Sent, Unidentified, 1760-1775 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: William Kempe, Letters Received, 1753-1759 and Undated
    Arranged alphabetically by sender. This subseries contains letters to William Kempe pertaining to court cases, and land disputes, including the Obling region. Correspondents also express complaints about neighbors, spouses, and masters, and request assistance.
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Received, A-C, 1753-1759 and Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Received, D-H, 1753-1759 and Undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Received, J-M, 1753-1759 and Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Received, N-T, 1753-1759 and Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Received, V-Y, 1753-1759 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 4: William Kempe, Letters Sent (Copies/Drafts), 1753-1757 and Undated
    Arranged alphabetically by recipient. This subseries contains William Kempe's letters that deal with pending court cases, and land disputes, especially the Oblong.
    - Correspondence: William Kempe, Letters Sent, 1753-1757 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5: Letters Between Others, 1730-1774 and Undated
    Arranged alphabetically by sender. This subseries contains letters between other correspondents regarding court cases, land issues, property and estate disputes, financial and shipping matters, and the New Hampshire land grants and riots.
    - Correspondence: Letters Between Others, A-C, 1730-1774 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Letters Between Others, D-L, 1730-1774 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Letters Between Others, M-V, 1730-1774 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Unidentified, 1732 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Legal Papers, 1760-1782 and Undated
  The bulk of this series is John Tabor Kempe's court agendas, 1760-1775. Most of the cases listed on these agendas appear to be in the Supreme Court of Judicature, though some may have been held in Sessions. Chancery cases are also included on some, listed separately. Agendas are quarterly (January, April, July, October) and contain lists of writs to be issued, pleas to be given or received, judgements to be entered, arguments, rolls to be filled, informations to be drawn, costs, and trials held for each quarter.
  Other items in the series include John Tabor Kempe's legal notes and opinions on various courts, legal definitions (esp. libel), authorities, trover cases, and unidentified court cases. Kempe's will, dated 1782, is also found in this series, as well as several power of attorney forms.
  - Legal Papers: Court Agendas, 1760-1765 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Legal Papers: Court Agendas, 1766-1769 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Legal Papers: Court Agendas, 1770-1775 Apr. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Legal Papers: John Tabor Kempe, Opinions and Notes, Undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Legal Papers: John Tabor Kempe, Will and Power of Attorney forms, 1766-1782 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Series 4: Land and Property Records, 1742-1775 and Undated
  This series contains items pertaining to New York's territorial disputes as well as land and property records, arranged by county, that do not appear to be connected with specific court cases.
  Items concerning the dispute over the Oblong region, between Connecticut and New York, include petitions, depositions, attornments, licenses, copies of agreements, and a statement of case. Further items regarding the Oblong in the John Tabor Kempe Papers were previously removed from the collection, and can now befound in BV New York State -- Boundaries -- Oblong. The New Hampshire land grant controversy, involving territory in present-day Vermont, is represented by petitions, depositions, notes, lists of grant holders, ordinances, recitals, reports, orders of Council, and Council minutes. Other material concerns disputes over borders with Massachusetts and New Jersey.
  County land and property records include a list of freeholders in Albany Co., surveys, boundaries, petitions, notes, patents, indentures, leases, and title/patent abstracts. Counties covered are Albany, Gloucester, Ulster, Kings, Orange, Westchester, and Suffolk.
  Also included in this series are items concerning John Tabor Kempe's house on Broadway, copies of the grant patent to the Duke of York in 1674, and instructions from the Crown regarding grants of land.
  - Land and Property Records: New York Borders, the Oblong, 1753 and Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Land and Property Records: New York Borders, Massachusetts and New Jersey, 1770, 1775 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Land and Property Records: New Hampshire grants, 1750-1775 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Land and Property Records: New Hampshire grants, Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Land and Property Records: Albany County, List of Freeholders, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Land and Property Records: Albany County, Patents, 1752-1753 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Land and Property Records: Albany County, Patents, 1761 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Land and Property Records: Albany County, Patents, 1761-1762 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Land and Property Records: Albany County, 1753-1771 and Undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Land and Property Records: Gloucester County, 1774 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Land and Property Records: Kings County, Undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Land and Property Records: Orange County, 1742-1762 and Undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Land and Property Records: Suffolk County, 1768-1770 and Undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Land and Property Records: Ulster County, 1774 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Land and Property Records: Westchester County, 1761-1762 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Land and Property Records: Multiple or Undetermined Counties, 1754-1771 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Land and Property Records: John Tabor Kempe, house on Broadway, 1772-1773 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Land and Property Records: Duke of York patent [copy]; instructions from the Crown, 1753-1763 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series 5: Financial Records, 1718-1775 and Undated
  This series contains John Tabor Kempe's lists of court fees for various courts, 1758-1771, including sheriffs', clerks', and judges' fees; accounts, bills, and receipts for John Tabor Kempe and William Kempe; accounts, bills, and receipts for others; and bonds for debts and shipping.
  - Financial Records: Court Fees, 1758-1771 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records: John Tabor Kempe and William Kempe; Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1753-1775 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records: Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1718-1770 and Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records: Bonds, 1758-1770 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Series 6: Government Records, 1722-1773 and Undated
  Included in this series are contemporary copies of Governor and Council records, particularly orders, concerning such topics as grants of land patents, charters for churches, and the burning of Zenger's journal; copies of various government acts, ordinances, charters, and orders (including an "act for more effectually collecting his Majesty's Quit Rents"); a 1764 report of John Tabor Kempe regarding fees for the Attorney General's office; and JTohn Tabor Kempe's appointments as Attorney General, with seals.
  - Government Records: Acts, Charters, Reports, etc., 1709-1774 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Government Records: Acts, Charters, Reports, etc., Undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Government Records: Governor and Council Orders, 1722-1773 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Government Records: John Tabor Kempe, appointment as Attorney General, 1759, 1768 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Series 7: Photograph, Undated
  One daguerreotype of a painted portrait, perhaps of John Tabor Kempe.
  - Photograph, Undated (Box 18, Folder 14)